Aboudou Razakou KONI

Address: Montréal, Québec, Canada

Phone: +1 514 970 9147 Mail: razackou@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/razakou/

Cloud/Solution Architect

SUMMARY

Highly skilled IT professional with almost 15 years of experience offering vast knowledge of all aspects of Information Technology.

Excellent at Full-stack web development, designing and implementing solutions, Project Management, solving complex Server, Storage, Network, Cloud and Security related issues.

Creative, self-starter with engaging attitude.

Eager to learn new systems and Technologies.

SKILLS

Java, Spring, Spring Boot, Python, HTML, CSS, React, Vue.js, JavaScript, Node.js, Full-stack, Bash, Automation and scripting, Amazon Web Service (AWS), Microsoft Azure, Microsoft 365, Cloud-Native Technologies, Cloud Security, Container orchestration, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (Amazon EKS), Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), Multi-cloud, Serverless, Microservice, Event-driven, Git, GitHub, CI/CD pipelines, Jenkins, Infrastructure as Code (IaC), Terraform, Ansible, APIs, AWS CloudFormation, AI & Machine Learning, Linux, DevOps, Data Backup, Network design and administration, ServiceNow, Business Continuity/Disaster Recovery, Security best practices, Microsoft Windows, Apache, Nginx, Monitoring, Zabbix, Prometheus, Grafana, Wireshark, Database Design and Management, VMware Virtualization, SAN, NAS, SQL/NoSQL Databases, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, MongoDB, Cloud Cost Optimization, Problem-solving, Communication, IT Service Management (ITSM), ITIL 4, Vendor management, Leadership, Communication, Problem-Solving, Business Acumen, TOGAF Architecture Principles, Project Management, Waterfall, Agile/Scrum, Continuous improvement/Six Sigma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Amazon Canada IT Support Engineer II 01/2023 to present

Technical leader of IT Team in Amazon warehouse facility located in Coteau-du-lac (YUL9).

- Network Automation
- AWS Infrastructure
- Scripting
- Microsoft Hyper-V
- Change Management coordination, administration and implementation
- IT Project management, coordination and Site Build across Canada
- Interaction with L4, L3 by providing training, mentorship and career progression guidance
- Develop and update of documentations

IT Specialist, Network and Maintenance 01/2020 to 12/2022

Providing professional, technical and operational support for Systems, Infrastructure and ICT services relating to acquisition, development, management and other ICT resource decisions across departments.

Notable accomplishments

- Maintenance plan for IT infrastructure
- Supported Virtual machines
- Supported network infrastructure (Cisco switches, Palo Alto Firewall, Ruckus Access points)
- Network monitoring (SolarWinds)
- VMWare vCenter Server & ESXi
- SAN (Storage Area Network; HP nimble)
- NAS (Synology, QNAP)
- Supported Unified communications (Cisco)
- Remote and onsite technical support

APM Terminals Cotonou

IT Specialist

08/2018 to 12/2019

Recognized as SME for datacenter and virtualization with a strong problem-solving capability, good communication skills and ability to multitask.

Notable accomplishments

- Backup of the IT Manager
- Supported 40+ Virtual machines with archiving and backups
- VMWare vCenter Server & ESXi
- Backup IT room design and build project
- Vehicle tracking system project
- Scripts for automation
- SAN (Storage Area Network; HP 3PAR)
- Backup, Recovery, and DR review/upgrade, tape library implementation
- Veeam Backup and Replication implementation
- Supported network infrastructure (Cisco & Mikrotik switches/routers, Altai & Mikrotik Access points)
- DMZ implementation
- Migration to Azure Active Directory
- Performed regular vulnerability assessments

APM Terminals Cotonou

IT Associate – Network, Systems & Data 06/2013 – 07/2018

Responsible for day-to-day maintenance services and update checks of servers hosting the company's resources. Ensuring smooth running of the organization's network architecture and datacenter.

Notable accomplishment

- Backup of the IT Manager
- Servers hardening (both Windows and Linux)
- Access control project

- Supported 30+ Virtual machines with archiving and backups
- VMWare vCenter Server & ESXi
- SAN (Storage Area Network; HP StorageWorks)
- NAS (Synology)
- CCTV networks project
- Supported network infrastructure (Cisco & Mikrotik switches/routers, Mikrotik Access points)
- Disaster recovery operations in SAN and virtual environment.
- Symantec/Veritas Backup Exec implementation
- LAN/WAN connections between multiple facilities.
- Network monitoring (Zabbix, The Dude)
- Deployed complex applications
- Documented network configuration and operational procedures.
- Rotation duty-phone help desk.

APM Terminals Cotonou IT Assistant 04/2011-05/2013

Was in charge of the installation/operation of computer systems and other technologies, such as printers, copiers, communication and presentation systems. My duties included tracking inventory, repairing equipment, and providing daily support for computer network users.

Notable accomplishment

- Performed hands-on administration, monitoring, and troubleshooting of LAN
- Stabilized, expanded and protected client network and PC environment.
- Build and deployed servers running Windows and Linux
- Implemented Zabbix, GLPI, OCS inventory NG for network devices monitoring and inventory
- Implemented Citrix VDI, SharePoint, WSUS, SQL Server, DHCP, Print and File server
- Liaised IT new equipment acquisition with procurement.
- Rotation duty-phone helpdesk.
- Inventory management of all the IT assets.
- Application design and development (Java)
- Installs, modifies and makes repairs to workstations
- Remote and onsite technical support

EDUCATION

- Master of Science, Systèmes, Réseaux et Sécurité School of Computer Engineering (ESGI), Paris, France
- Bachelor of Science, Réseaux et Télécommunications
 University of the Littoral Opal Coast (ULCO), Calais-Boulogne, France
- Brevet de Technicien Superieur (BTS), Informatique de Gestion
 University of Management Science and Technology (ESGIS), Cotonou, Benin

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM)
- Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA) (in progress)

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Project Management Foundations
- Cisco CCNP Enterprise
- VMware Certified Professional Data Center Virtualization
- ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management
- CompTIA Security+
- CompTIA Linux+

PERSONAL DETAILS

• Languages: English, French (Bilingual) and Spanish (Basic)

Age: 34

• Interests: New technologies, Motorsports, Fitness, Travels